Guide to the Property Plats Collection, Circa 1925-1932
Duke University. University Archives
Property Plats circa 1925-1932
Duke University. University Archives
Duke Construction Company.
Extent: 18 Oversize Folders, 1 Oversize Box Extent: 200 Items
Although the exact provenance of the property plats is unknown, it is indicated on the reverse side of some plats that the surveys were used by A. C. Lee, Chief Engineer of the Duke Construction Company and the plats may have been created by the Atlantic Realty Company. This collection includes approximately 100 survey plats of Duke University properties prior to the construction on East Campus and West Campus from the years 1925-1926. Also included are plats representing the Duke Homestead from 1932 that were possibly drawn by V.A. Stewman.
RL.01798
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Property Plats were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1979.
Collection Overview
This collection includes approximately 100 survey plats of Duke University properties prior to the construction on East Campus and West Campus from the years 1925-1926. Some plats represent part of what is now Duke Forest. The plats show details of the topography and terrain, roads and streets, bodies of water, trees and buildings. A key map is included. On the reverse side of some plats, it is indicated that the surveys were used by A. C. Lee, Chief Engineer of the Duke Construction Company and the plats may have been produced by the Atlantic Realty Company. Also included are plats representing the Duke Homestead from 1932 that were possibly drawn by V.A. Stewman. Topics include Duke Construction Company, East Campus, West Campus, Duke Forest and the Duke Homestead.
Drawings are pen and pencil on paper mounted to cloth, measuring approximately 23"x30", organized according to geographic locations The scale is approximately 50 feet to the inch.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke Construction Company; Duke Forest (N.C.) -- Maps; Duke Homestead (Durham, N.C.); Duke University -- East Campus; Duke University -- West Campus; Plats (maps)
Detailed Description of Collection
- Property Plats, circa 1925-1932, 19 Oversize Folders, 1 Oversize Box
  The individual plats can be assembled to show all of East and West Campuses, and there is a key which shows how the plats fit together. On the key, plats are organized by section number. Likewise, plats listed below are grouped by section.
  - East Campus and key, circa 1925-1926 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Central and West Campus, circa 1925-1926 (Opaperfolder 2-4)
  - West Campus, circa 1925-1926 (Opaperfolder 5-7)
  - West Campus, circa 1925-1926 (Opaperfolder 8-10)
  - Duke Forest (not located on map key, circa 1925-1926 (Opaperfolder 11-12)
  - West Campus, circa 1925-1926 (Opaperfolder 13-15)
  - Duke Forest, circa 1925-1926 (Opaperfolder 16-17)
  - Duke Homestead Plats, 1932 (Opaperfolder 18)
  - Duke Forest, Durham Division, 1925 (Opaperfolder 19)
  - Property Plats and Key, copy 2, circa 1925-1926 (Box 1 (oversize))